Finding Aid for the Collection of Heavy Metal Music Material LSC.2269
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Photographs, ephemera, and memorabilia, 1970-2015
  - Roxx Gang fan club letters, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Slipknot concert memorabilia: Ozzfest memorabilia, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 11, Box 9)
    Concert set list for August 14, 2004 Ozzfest performance in East Troy, Wisconsin, signed by Joey Jordison, Corey Taylor, and Craig Jones. Time sheets for both stages. Color artwork for "Vol. 3: The Subliminal Verses." Three 3" x 5" color photographs of vocalist Corey Taylor.
  - Slipknot concert memorabilia: tour t-shirt, 2004 (Box 9)
    Black t-shirt, size extra large.
  - Slipknot concert memorabilia: Joey Jordison signature drumsticks, 2004 (Box 9)
  - Suicidal Tendencies and No Mercy photographs and ephemera, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    23 photographs, mostly 3.5" x 5". Also includes 5 rub-on decals.
  - Tuff fan club newsletter, flyer, and postcard, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Archie Meets Kiss", 2011 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Comic book signed by Paul Stanley of KISS, writer Alex Segura, and artist Dan Parent.
  - KISS bubble gum cards, 1978 (Box 12)
    First and second series, complete 132 card set. Two original card packs, sealed.
  - Kiss makeup, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Intact package of makeup including white and black creams; black, blue, green, and red crayons, an applicator, a sponge, and three fake blood capsules.
    Gift of The Book Shop.
  - Backstage passes album, 1970s-1980s; Most passes are printed on satin and feature logos and original art corresponding to the tour. (Box 10)
    Collection of 70 backstage passes from the 1970s-2000s, for bands such as Aerosmith, Iron Maiden, Ozzy Osbourne, Motley Crue, Rush, Judas Priest, L. A. Guns, Motorhead, Pantera, Dio, Dokken, and Metallica.
  - Concert photo album, 1987-1989 (Box 14)
    Photographs of Leatherwolf, Warrant, Icon, Hurricane, XYZ, Keel, and Def Leppard. Three sheets of slides of Poison. Also includes a photographer's pass for the Scorpions' Crazy World Tour. Photographer unidentified. 122 color photos, mostly 6" x 4"; and 44 black & white photos, mostly 3" x 5."
  - Poison fan photo album, 1988 (Box 14)
    Photographs featuring unknown female fan with members of Poison, Megadeth, and Cinderella. Also includes backstage pass to the Empire Rock Club in Philadelphia, PA, and a photo of a cake celebrating the release of Poison's album, "Open Up and Say... Ahh!" 27 color photographs, mostly 3.5" x 5."
  - Flyers of the Sunset Strip, 2015; Metal cover, with bass tuning knobs along the spine. (Box 15)
    Contains reproductions of original band flyers collected by Mike Schneider on the Sunset Strip, with his commentary on the bands featured, such as Taz, PairADice, Poison, Razzle, and Tuff. Featured venues include the Roxy, the Whisky a Go-Go, the Troubadour, the Cathouse, the Country Club, the Rainbow Bar & Grill, and Gazzarri's. Also includes reproductions of band photos, club tickets, and business cards.
    Edition 53 of 60.
- Series 4: Zines, 1976-2016
  These are independently produced, typically small-circulation periodicals that describe local music scenes or pertain to particular bands. Includes zines from California as well as from throughout the United States and other countries.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by zine title.
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Aquelarre Zine, #15, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Aura, 2000s (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Published in Cadiz, Spain.
  - Ball Buster, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Baphometal, Part 3, 2008 November (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Bells of Archeron, circa 2012 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Black Market, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - The Beyond, volume 3, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Colophon reads in part, "All layout, material, and most art work summoned by the Vessel of Satan; J."
  - Braincandy, 1978 October (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Brain Damage, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Issues 1 (Fall 1984) and 2 (Spring 1985) published in Long Beach, CA; founded by Vadim Rubin and Ron Nieto.
  - Brainstorm magazine, #2, 1993 May-October (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - The Brutal Adventures of Black Metal Girl, 2015-2016 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Gift of The Book Shop, June 2016.
    Graphic novel. Issue 1. "The first issue of Black Metal Girl finds Alastrina face-to-face with one of the greatest enemies of all time... the youtube commenter." Illustrated by Drake Hernandez. Cover Art by April Dimmick. Written by Aris Garner and Travis Sylvies. Created by Aris Garner.
    Issue 2. "Fun Times at Death Metal High Super Awesome Activity Comic Book."
  - The Brutal Adventures of Black Metal Girl, #2, 2016 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Bulldozer Magazine, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Buried #5, 2014 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Burning Salts, 2014 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Issues 1 and 2. Editor and publisher Bryer Wharton.
  - Call To The Infernal Hordes Zine, #5, 2009 February (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - The Convivial Hermit, 2008, 2010 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Darkness Against Light Fiercezine, circa 2010 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Deadhead, #3, #4, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Death n' Armageddon Mag, #6, 2004 October (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Defiance of Gothic Nirvana X, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Defiled Metalzine, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Desecration of Virgin Magazine, 2000s (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Devilment Zine, 2000s (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Devilment Zine, 2006 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Distorted, #2, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Doom Hauled, circa 1998 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Dreams of Abel, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Dungeongrease, #4, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Evil Assault, circa 2007 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - The Fallout Magazine, #9, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Fatal Underground, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - First Tour Problems, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    A chronicle of a five week tour with a metalcore band given the pseudonym "Sky Falling" written by Maxx, a soundtech and tour manager. The author "wanted to show the tougher parts of touring as a crewmember, but that there is also fun to be had," and dedicates the zine to "all the other soundgirls out there."
  - From Beyond Zine, 2002-2003 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - F.T.Y.K.P. Misanthrozine, circa 2003 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Funeral Maelstrom of Hate, #2, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - The Future World of Rock, circa 1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Gallery of the Grotesque, circa 1998 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Gallery of the Grotesque, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - GASP, etc., #1, 1993 Spring (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Grave Wave Extreme Music Magazine, February 2015 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - The Grimoire of Exalted Deeds, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - GWAR, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Book featuring comics that were originally published by Dark Horse Comics in DEADLINE U. S. A. All the stories written and drawn by the artists who design and build the props, costumes, and effects for GWAR's live show and also perform as characters on stage. Published by Slave Pit Inc., Richmond, VA.
  - GWAR, circa 1988 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Headbanger, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    No. 4, 5, 6, 10. Edited by Bob Nalbandian. Published in Huntington Beach, CA.
  - Headbanger Magazine, #9, 2007 January (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Heaven's Metal, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Heavy Cream, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Number 1 (April 2014) and 2 (September 2014), published in Los Angeles by Adam Murray. Includes stickers and a poster.
  - Heavy Metal: Akron's Only Rock Informer, December 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Volume 1, number 9, published in Akron, Ohio.
  - Hectic Metal Magazine, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Hellpike, circa 2002 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Heresy Magazine, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Hollyrock Babylon: a heavy metal tabloid, undated (circa 1989-90) (Box 19, Folder 12)
    Volume 1, numbers 2 and 3. West Hollywood, CA. Senior writer Bambi LaRue. Includes news, gossip, fan fiction, record reviews, interviews, and advertisements for Los Angeles record shops, tattoo artists, etc.
    Purchase from The Book Shop, Covina, CA.
  - Horrified Death Metal Fanzine, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Intellectual Spew, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Ink Disease, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Issue number 9. Edited by Thomas Siegel (?). Published in Los Angeles. Features an interview with Kirk Hammett and James Hetfield of Metallica, an unusual offering in a punk-centric zine.
  - Kentucky Fried Afterbirth, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    Issues 5 & 6.
  - Klasma Zine, circa 2006 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Kremlin Kore, circa 1999 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Leather n' Spikes, circa 1999 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Little Bouncing Bunnies #2, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Lucifer's Hammer, 2000s (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Mainstream Resistance, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Metal Core, 1990s (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Metal Meltdown: Straight from the Infernal Wasteland, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    10 issues (complete run). Published in Severna Park, Maryland by Jeff "KLUKE" Vanderclute, and others.
  - Metal Storm, 2008, 2010 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Content by Hellthrasher.
  - Morbid Tales, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Necromaniac Zine, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Necroscope Metalzine, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Necroscope 'zine, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Noise and Shit, 2000s (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Nokturnal Subjugation, 2016 December (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Northern Heritage, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - The Other Side underground metal newsletter, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Pagan Pages, #8, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Paradise Noise, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Promethean Crusade, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Proximity, a Led Zeppelin newspaper, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    9 tabloid issues. Published in Issaquah and Seattle, edited by Juli LeCompte and Hugh Jones.
  - Psicoterror, circa 2000 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Rebel Beat, September 1986 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Published in Fairfield, NJ by Tami "Odie" Morgan. Signed by Anthrax guitarist Scott Ian on the front panel. Contains transcripts of interviews Morgan conducted with Jon Oliva of Savatage, Raven's John Gallagher, and Scott Ian, among others, all of whom are asked for their opinion on rock censorship. Also includes a review of Flotsam and Jetsam's 1985 Metal Shock demo featuring future Metallica bassist Jason Newsted.
  - Remnants of Reason, 2000, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Satanic Terrorist Elite, 2000s (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Satan's Candy Basket, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Satan's Sadist, 2009 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Sin Dios zine and CD, circa 1999 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - So What! The Metallica Club Magazine, 2015 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Volume 22, numbers 2-4.
  - Subculture, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Temple of Adoration, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Thrash Attack, 2000s (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Treats from the Underground, 2000 January (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Unhallowed Magazine, circa 2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Wasted Paper, 2016 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Web: A Literary Journal of Extreme Music and Entertainment, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Wormgear, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Vampiria, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - What Gives Fanzine, Audiocassette, and Memorabilia, 2016 (Box 12)
    Includes installment 5 of What Gives Fanzine in envelope with pin and sticker, audiocasette labelled "A collection of classic demo tracks," and a number of stickers and pins, all housed together in plastic bag.
- Series 5: Magazines, 1968-2016
  These periodicals were commercially produced, with large-scale circulation. Includes mostly single issues that feature metal-related articles, including the May 11, 1968 issue of Rolling Stone, which features the first documented use of the term "heavy metal."
  - The Advocate, 1998 May 12 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Featuring the article "Rob Halford: Between a Rock and a Hard Place" by Judy Wieder, about the frontman of Judas Priest.
  - D2 Magazine, 2016 January 15 (Box 10)
    Norwegian magazine (Friday insert in magazine Dagens Næringsliv).
  - Kerrang!, 1982-1990 (Box 7, Folder 1-3, Box 6, Folder 4-5, Box 8)
    57 issues:
    Box 6. Issue numbers 14, 62, 65, 67, 69, 70, 72, 73, 76, 77, 79, 81, 82, 84, 85.
    Box 7. Issue numbers 86, 89, 90, 91, 92, 95, 96, 97, 98, 101, 102, 103, 104, 106, 108, 113, 117 (2 copies), 118, 119, 121.
    Box 8. Issue numbers 122, 136, 137, 143, 149, 160-162, 178, 187, 189, 191, 197, 203, 207, 225, 229, 246, 269, 295.
  - Kerrang! Lemmy Special Tribute Issue, 2016 January 9 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - LA Weekly, 2008 November 21-27 (Box 10)
    Feature article, "Norwegian Black Metal: Mother Nature Makes Vicious Vikings out of Little Boys."
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Music Life, 1988 November (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Rolling Stone, 1968 May 11 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Includes the first documented use of the term "heavy metal" in a review of the album "A Long Time Comin'" by Electric Flag.
- Series 6: Recordings, 1969-2015
  CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  Vinyl records, audiocassettes, and compact disc albums of heavy metal music from 1968-2015. Some album cases signed by artists. Records are 12 inches unless otherwise noted.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by artist name.
  - Anthrax, Got the Time, 1990; Vinyl record (10 inch). (Box 11)
  - Author and Punisher/Harassor, Fearce, 2014; Vinyl record (7 inch). (Box 26)
  - Black Sabbath, Heaven and Hell, 1980; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Black Sabbath, Heaven and Hell, 1980; 8-track, audiocassette, and compact disc. (Box 12)
  - Coven, Witchcraft Destroys Minds & Reaps Souls, 1969; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
    - Witchcraft Destroys Minds and Reaps Souls, 1969; yrlsc_2269_011_001a; Mercury Record Corporation; 1 sound recordings (1 vinyl record; Duration: 0:23:13); Condition Note: label on disc reads "Side 2" on both sides due to a manufacturer's error (Box 11, Case 1)
    - Witchcraft Destroys Minds and Reaps Souls, 1969; yrlsc_2269_011_001b; Mercury Record Corporation; 1 sound recordings (1 vinyl record; Duration: 0:22:35); Condition Note: label on disc reads "Side 2" on both sides due to a manufacturer's error (Box 11, Case 1)
  - Darkthrone, Cromlech, 1989 (Box 12)
    An early issue of the original demo tape, featuring three tracks: The Watchtower, Accumulation of Generalization, and Sempiternal Past / Presence View Sepulchrality (later versions feature the song "Iconoclasm Sweeps Cappodocia"). Recorded live in November 1989, and copied onto a TDK D90 audiocassette.
  - Deathkings/Rozamov, 2014-2015; Vinyl record (7 inch). (Box 26)
  - Friend, Lonn. Pirate Radio Saturday Night promotional cassette, circa 1992; Audiocassette and plastic case housed in airsickness bag. Signed by Lonn Friend. (Box 12)
  - Guns N' Roses, Appetite for Destruction, 1987; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Iron Maiden, Maiden Japan, 1981; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Judas Priest, British Steel, 1980; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Legion Canada, Spring Offensive, 2015 (Box 26)
    Vinyl record (7 inch), compact disc, Floppy Noise Records business cards, and Kriegzine.
  - Metallica, Master of Puppets, 1986; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Metallica, No Life 'Til Leather, 1982; Copied onto a TDK D60 audiocassette, accompanied by the photo-mechanically reproduced insert, and housed in a plastic case. (Box 12)
    Later issue of the original demo tape, lacking the printed cassette label. Seven tracks: (Hit the Lights, The Mechanics, Motorbreath, Seek & Destroy, Metal Militia, Jump in the Fire, and Phantom Lord) recorded by Metallica's original line up: James Hetfield, Dave Mustaine, Ron McGovney (uncredited), and Lars Ulrich (bassist Cliff Burton is included in the band member list, but a note below reads: "Burton does not play on this tape).
  - Motley Crue, Generation Swine, 1999; Compact disc. Signed cover booklet. (Box 12)
  - Myrkur, M, 2015; Vinyl record, in wooden case. (Box 27)
  - Owen Hart, In Death, 2006; Compact disc and vinyl record (5 inch). (Box 26)
  - Pantera, Metal Magic, 1983; Vinyl record, sealed in original shrink wrap. (Box 11)
  - Pantera, Projects in the Jungle, 1984; Vinyl record, sealed in original shrink wrap. (Box 11)
  - Poison, Look What the Cat Dragged In, 1986; Vinyl record, sealed in original shrink wrap. (Box 11)
  - Prong, Force Fed, 1988; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Queensryche, Queensryche, 1983; Vinyl record, sealed in original shrink wrap. (Box 11)
  - Quiet Riot, Metal Health, 1983; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Sadistic Intent, Conflict Within, 1989; Copied onto a TDK D60 audiocassette labeled "Sadistic Intent" in blue ink on the A side and "Dark Angel" in black ink on the B side. (Box 12)
    Original demo tape, featuring six tracks: Conflict Within, No Reason, Doomed To Live, Speak For Yourself, Existance [sic], and Morbid Faith. Recorded at Cage Studios in Los Angeles in February 1989. The space left blank on this tape was filled with Darkness Descends, the second album by Los Angeles thrash band Dark Angel.
  - Sadistic Intent, Reawakening Horrid Thoughts, 2014; Vinyl record. Signed album cover. (Box 11)
  - Samhain: On Earth as it is in Hell (Live), 1989; Vinyl record (7 inch). (Box 11)
    Bootleg recording of five songs performed live at Wabash Hall in San Diego, California on May 2, 1985
  - Samhain, Die Die My Darling, 1984; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - Slayer, Reign in Blood, 1986; Vinyl record. (Box 11)
  - S.O.D.: Stormtroopers of Death, Speak English or Die, 1985; Vinyl record, signed by guitarist Scott Ian. (Box 11)
  - Sound Barrier, The Speed of Light, 1986; Vinyl record. Cover signed by artists. (Box 11)
  - Stryper, To Hell with the Devil, 1986; Vinyl record, sealed in original shrink wrap. (Box 11)
  - Suicidal Tendencies, not dated; Vinyl record. Handwritten song list: I'm your nitemare, Widespread Bloodshed, Own Way of Life, Waking the Dead, No Mercy. (Box 11)
  - Various artists, Metal for Muthas, 1980; Vinyl record. Signed on the front panel by four members of the band Toad The Wet Sprocket: Mike Mustafa, Mark Ridout, Peter Austin, and Martin Wightwick. (Box 11)
    Includes songs by Iron Maiden, Sledgehammer, and Angel Witch among others.
  - Venom, Black Metal, 1986; Vinyl record (picture disc). (Box 11)